Indiana University Folklore Students' Association records, 1972-2009 C385
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Folklore Students' Association records
1972-2009
1978-1984
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Students' Association
C385
1 cubic feet
The Folklore Students' Association (FSA) is a student run organization supported by the Department of Folklore and Ethnomusicology and Indiana University. The collection consists of correspondence, newsletters, meeting minutes and reports.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research. Advanced notice required for access.
Administrative History
The Folklore Students' Association (FSA) is a student run organization supported by the Department of Folklore and Ethnomusicology and Indiana University.
FSA strives to provide support for IU folklore students, both graduate and undergraduate. FSA encourages members to broaden their personal horizons by providing opportunities to meet, work with, and exchange ideas with other developing scholars in the field. The association also seeks to build professional interests in members through such means as development workshops that bring in faculty and other professionals to speak with students on a variety of current issues in the discipline. Perhaps the most crucial objective is promoting the folklore discipline. By giving members opportunities to develop both personally and professionally, FSA seeks to aid them in preparing for their emergence as the next generation of folklore scholars. Likewise, in expanding the role of folklorists as both participants in and organizers of community events, FSA endeavors to bring folklore into the spotlight as a scholastic discipline. Through encouraging the efforts of students and facilitating familiarity with folklore among the communities in which we live, work, and study, FSA ultimately aims to propagate overall awareness of and interest in folklore as a vibrant sphere of academia.
Folklore Students' Association website: http://folksa.wordpress.com/
Arrangement
Collection is organized into three series: Administrative files, Meeting minutes and reports, and Newsletters.
Scope and Content Note
The Folklore Students' Association records comprise .6 cubic feet of records spanning the period from 1972 to 2009. There are three series in this collection, Administrative files, 1972-1984, Meeting minutes and reports, 1977-1983, and Newsletters, 1977-1992.
The Administrative files span the period from 2009 and contain the Charter, resolutions, business and financial records, and documentation pertaining to a student conference organized by the FSA Student Paper Conferences.
The second series, Meeting minutes and reports, spans the period from 1977-1988. This series contains the minutes recorded at student and faculty meetings for the Folklore Students' Association, as well as committee reports filed. The minutes reflect the issues the FSA dealt with, such as course offerings, graduate student research, and even faculty appointments. The records are not complete.
The third series, Newsletters spans the period from 1977-1992. The monthly, sometimes biweekly, newsletters published by the Folklore Students' Association are contained within this series. The newsletter reports on issues affecting the student and faculty body in the field of folklore, such as course offerings, student research projects, publication announcements, and faculty appointments.
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory http://institutionalmemory.iu.edu/aim/
Archived web sites for this organization may be included in Archive-It: http://www.archive-it.org/collections/219
Acquisition Information
Accession Information: 2003/055
Provenance
Transferred from the Indiana University Folklore Department, 2003.
College students --Social life and customs --Archives.; College students --Intellectual life --Archives.; Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Students' Association -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Students' Association -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University, Bloomington. Folklore Students' Association -- Periodicals; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Folklore and Ethnomusicology -- students -- Intellectual life -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Folklore and Ethnomusicology -- students -- Social life and customs -- Archives
- Administrative files, 1972-2009 (Box 1)
  - Business and Finances, 1973-1978 (Box 1)
  - Charter, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Conference Information and Programs, 2009 (Box 1)
    General
    (Posters stored with oversized materials. Consult archivist for details.)
  - Faculty Evaluations, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Folklore Institute Curriculum Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Job descriptions, undated (Box 1)
  - Meeting schedules and notes, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Museum Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1)
    - General (Box 1)
      - undated (Box 1)
      - March 1990 (Box 1)
  - Resolution on Social Issues and Responses, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Student Organization Account, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Student Paper Conferences, 1979-1984 (Box 1)
  - General (Box 1)
    - 1974-1987 (Box 1)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 1)
- Meeting minutes and reports, 1977-1988 (Box 1)
  - Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - 1981 (Box 1)
    - 1983 (Box 1)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Committee Reports, 1978 (Box 1)
- Newsletters, 1977-1992 (Box 1)
  - 1977 (Box 1)
  - 1978 (Box 1)
  - 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 1)